zebra.com 2019-12-31

# Privacy Statement | Zebra Technologies

### **ZEBRA PRIVACY STATEMENT**

This Zebra Privacy Statement ("Privacy Statement") describes how Zebra Technologies Corporation and its subsidiaries and affiliates ("Zebra") collect, use, transfer, and disclose data including personally identifiable information (“Personal Information”) obtained through Zebra’s websites (the "Site(s)") and via other methods.  By using the Sites or submitting any Personal Information to Zebra, you acknowledge that you have read, understood, and agree to be bound by this Privacy Statement and the Zebra **Terms of Use**.

This Privacy Statement also describes certain matters related to the EU-U.S. Privacy Shield and Swiss-U.S. Privacy Shield frameworks. Zebra has certified it adheres to EU-U.S. Privacy Shield framework and the Swiss-U.S Privacy Shield framework.  To learn more and view Zebra’s Privacy Shield Policy click here.

### **DATA ZEBRA COLLECTS**

Zebra collects data to provide customers with products and services, and to operate Zebra’s business. Some of this data is provided directly, such as when you create a Zebra account, connect a Zebra device to the Internet or a Cloud service, provide equipment for maintenance, or contact Zebra for support or to perform other services.  Zebra receives some data by recording how users interact with Zebra products and services by, for example, using technologies like Cookies, receiving error reports, usage data or location data from software running on Zebra products or from utilizing Zebra services.

The data Zebra collects depends on the products, services and features used, and can include the following:

_**Name and contact data**_. Information, including Personal Information, collected through the Sites or through other means, may include name and salutation, job title, physical address, time zone, telephone number (including work or home office, mobile, and fax numbers), photograph, e-mail address, and other contact information. Zebra also collects marketing contacts and preferences (phone, email, postal mail, fax, and text messages), name and nature of your business, language preference, and delivery and fulfillment information.

_**Credentials**_ **.** Zebra collects information used for authentication and account access.

_**Payment data**_. Zebra or its payment processor collects data necessary to process payments for purchases from Zebra, such as credit/debit card information, bank information, wire transfer and/or any other financial or payment information associated with a payment.

_**Usage data**_. Zebra collects data about how users and devices interact with Zebra products and services. For example, Zebra collects:

_**Product use data**_ **.** Zebra collects product feature use data, website activity data, performance data, product preference information, purchase history, and the webpages you visit.

_**Device data**_ **.** Zebra may collect data about a device, its operational state, configuration, past usage data, device performance data, and information on the network used to connect and use Zebra products. This includes data about the operating systems, applications and other software installed on the device, including product keys. This also includes Internet Protocol (IP) address, network authentication, MAC address, other device identifiers, regional and language settings.

_**Error reports and performance data**_. Zebra collects data about the performance of Zebra products and problems experienced. This data helps diagnose problems in the products to improve Zebra’s products, and to provide solutions. Depending on product and settings, error reports may include data such as the type or severity of the problem, details of the software or hardware related to an error, device status, usage data, contents of data or files that were processing when an error occurred, and data about other devices, networks, or software with which the device interacts.

_**Support data**_. When Zebra is engaged for support, Zebra’s contact with any data or information stored on a device will be incidental in most instances.  Devices returned to Zebra for repair should be wiped of all data.  Zebra will collect data about any hardware, software, and other details related to the support incident for the purpose of tracking device performance and product improvement.

_**Location data**_. Zebra may collect data about your location, which can be either precise or imprecise. Precise location data can be Global Position System (GPS) data, as well as data identifying nearby cell towers and Wi-Fi hotspots Zebra collects when location-based products or features are enabled. Imprecise location data includes, for example, a location derived from your IP address or other data that indicates the geolocation of an IP address with less precision including latitude, longitude, city, region, country or postal code.

_**Cookies**_. Sites may collect certain kinds of data which could encompass Personal Information during your visit, including through the use of Cookies. Cookies are small text files sent from a site to the hard drive of a user's device to store bits of information related to that user or device. Cookies can store information about the device and users, including IP addresses, navigational data, server information, data transfer times, user preferences, and passwords needed to access the special areas on Zebra Sites. Zebra uses Cookies to assist with the downloading of documents from Sites and for other business purposes such as traffic analysis of Sites. If you choose to create a user profile, Zebra will use Cookies to store the Personal Information for your profile. Your browser may be able to be configured to block, reject, remove or disable Cookies and other tracking technologies. However, if you reject or remove Cookies or other tracking technology, you might not be able to access certain pages or use important functions on Sites, including downloading documents and establishing a user profile.

_**Other Technology**_ **.** Sites also use IP addresses, log files and other technology to identify Site problems and usage. Zebra also uses Web beacons to perform standard traffic analysis on the Sites in a manner similar to how Zebra uses Cookies and to track Site(s) usage for statistical purposes. Zebra reserves the right to introduce new tracking technologies and techniques related to the use of the Sites, although Zebra will do so subject to and in accordance with applicable data protection laws and regulations.

### **HOW ZEBRA USES PERSONAL INFORMATION**

Zebra uses, discloses, transfers, and otherwise processes data, including Personal Information, in several ways. Zebra uses the data it collects for three basic purposes: (1) to process transactions for the sale and support of Zebra products and/or services, (2) to operate Zebra’s business, and to provide and support the products and services Zebra offers (including improving and personalizing), and (3) to send certain communications, including promotional communications. When customers place an order, Zebra uses the Personal Information provided, including any payment information necessary to provide the products or services requested.  If you create a user profile, Zebra will store Personal Information as requested to manage the profile and communicate with the user. **  **Without limiting our obligations under our **Privacy Shield Policy**, if you are located outside of the United States, please be aware that any information you provide to Zebra through the Sites may be transferred to the United States.  Please also be aware that by using the Sites and giving Zebra your information, you consent to such transfer. You also understand that the U.S. may not provide the same level of protections as the laws of your country.

Personal Information may also, subject to the requirements of applicable law, be used, disclosed and transferred to law enforcement personnel and other persons in situations where Zebra believes that it is necessary to identify, contact, or bring legal proceedings against someone who may be misusing the Sites, interfering with the rights of Zebra or other users, or when Zebra reasonably believes that the law requires or permits such disclosure.

### **WHY ZEBRA SHARES PERSONAL INFORMATION**

Zebra shares Personal Information with consent or as necessary to complete any transaction or provide any product or service requested or authorized. Zebra also may disclose and transfer Personal Information to channel partners, strategic partners, suppliers and other third parties for the purposes described in this Privacy Statement and to assist with the operation of the Sites and/or the associated business transactions.  If Zebra sells or divests all or part of its business, makes a transfer of assets, or otherwise becomes involved in a change of control transaction, or in the unlikely event of bankruptcy, Zebra may transfer Personal Data covered by this Privacy Shield Policy to one or more third parties as part of the transaction including the due diligence process.

Additionally, Zebra will access, transfer, disclose, and preserve Personal Information when Zebra has a good faith belief that doing so is necessary to:

  1. comply with applicable law or respond to valid legal process, including from law enforcement or other government agencies;
  2. protect our customers, for example to prevent unsolicited emails or attempts to defraud users of Zebra products, or to help prevent the loss of life or serious injury of anyone;
  3. operate and maintain the security of Zebra’s products and services, including to prevent or stop an attack on Zebra’s computer systems or networks; or
  4. protect the rights or property of Zebra, including enforcing the terms governing the use of the products or services; however, if Zebra receives information indicating that someone is using Zebra products or services to traffic in stolen intellectual or physical property, Zebra may refer the matter to law enforcement.

### **DATA SECURITY**

Pursuant to applicable regulations, Zebra maintains reasonable technical and administrative procedures to protect data including Personal Information against accidental or unlawful destruction or accidental loss, alteration, unauthorized disclosure or access. Zebra cannot guarantee any data’s absolute security or warrant the security of any data against any possible loss or unauthorized access.

### **ACCESS AND CORRECTION OF PERSONAL INFORMATION**

If you wish to access or update the Personal Information submitted through the Sites, or to make any inquiries (including requests of cancellation or deletion) about the collection or processing of such information, please contact us as described below in the section labeled "Contact" or in the **Privacy Shield Policy** as applicable.  Zebra provides individuals with access to their Personal Information where required by applicable data protection and privacy laws.  Individuals will be required to sufficiently verify their identity. Declining to provide Personal Information may limit Zebra’s ability to respond to your inquiry.

### **LINKS TO OTHER INTERNET SITES**

The statements set forth in this Privacy Statement are for the Sites and other activities.  Other sites hosted by third parties may have different practices. If you link to or otherwise visit any other sites managed by third parties, you must review the privacy policies posted at those sites.  Zebra has no control over those sites and is not responsible or liable for the policies and practices followed by third parties.

### **RETENTION OF DATA**

Zebra will keep your data, which may include Personal Information, for as long as necessary for the purposes for which it was collected, to provide you with products or services, to conduct legitimate business interests, and where otherwise required or permitted by law.

### **GENERAL DATA PROTECTION REGULATION (GDPR)**

The GDPR Addendum applies in circumstances where Zebra’s privacy practices are subject to the EU General Data Protection Regulation (“GDPR”). If applicable to you, the GDPR Addendum should be read in conjunction with this Privacy Policy.

### **CALIFORNIA PRIVACY DISCLOSURES**

Effective January 1, 2020, under the California Consumer Privacy Act of 2018 (CCPA), California residents have the following new rights in respect to their personal information:

  1. The right to request the deletion of any Personal Information about the consumer that has been collected from the consumer;
  2. The right to request disclosures regarding the collection of Personal Information;
  3. The right to request disclosures regarding the sale of Personal Information or disclosures made for a business purpose;
  4. The right not to be discriminated against for exercising his/her rights under the CCPA;
  5. The right to opt-out of the sale of Personal Information; and
  6. The right to opt-in for minors; and,
  7. The right to opt-in for any financial incentive programs.

**Right to Deletion and Disclosure of Personal Information**

Twice within a 12-month period, California residents, with whom Zebra has an established business relationship, may make a personal information request. Zebra will need to collect information from you to verify your identity before this request can be fulfilled. You may also request that personal information not being used for a business purpose be deleted.

A request may be made to access personal information by emailing [privacy@zebra.com](mailto:privacy@zebra.com), calling 877 561 8503 or writing us at:

Privacy Office  
3 Overlook Place  
Lincolnshire, IL 60004

**Right to Opt Out of Sales**

If you are a California resident, you may opt-out of any sale of your personal information to the extent enabled by California law by emailing us at [privacy@zebra.com](mailto:privacy@zebra.com), calling 877 561 8503 or writing us at:

Privacy Office  
3 Overlook Place  
Lincolnshire, IL 60004

**Right to Not Be Discriminated Against**

Zebra does not discriminate on the basis of consumer rights requests.

**Right to Opt-out**

Zebra may use third-party ad servers (or ad networks) to deliver ads to you on our behalf. These third-party ad servers may collect and use non-personal information about your visits to our site in order to present advertisements that may be of interest to you. If you would like more information about this practice or to opt-out of having this information used by third-party ad servers to provide targeted ads, please visit <https://www.networkadvertising.org/managing/opt_out.asp>.

### **Unsubscribing from Emails**

If you are currently receiving emails from Zebra and wish to be removed from a communication, unsubscribe by using the unsubscribe link in the email or click [here](https://connect.zebra.com/Preferences-enu) to remove yourself from our mailing list.

### **Children’s Privacy**

We do not knowingly solicit children to purchase our services or products. Our websites are not designed to attract children under the age of 13 and we do not intentionally or knowingly collect Personal Information on our websites from anyone under the age of 13.

### **OTHER COUNTRY PRIVACY STATEMENTS THAT MAY APPLY**

The following Policy Statements apply to the indicated countries:

Argentina – Aviso de Privacidad Para Argentina  
Colombia – Politica de Tratamiento de Datos Personales  
Mexico – Aviso de Privacidad Integral Para Mexico  
Spanish – Declaración de Privacidid

**REVISIONS TO THIS PRIVACY STATEMENT  **

Zebra reserves the right to change this Privacy Statement from time to time at Zebra’s discretion consistent with legal, contractual, and regulatory requirements. Please check this Privacy Statement frequently and particularly before you submit Personal Information via the Sites.  

### **CONTACT**

If you have any questions about this Privacy Statement, please contact us at:

**Zebra Technologies Corporation**  
International Headquarters  
Attn: Legal Department  
3 Overlook Point  
Lincolnshire, IL 60069 USA  
Email: [Privacy@Zebra.com](mailto:Privacy@Zebra.com)  
Phone:  **+1 847 464-8010**

V5 Date: December 29, 2019
